I'd say welcome brothers and sisters to
another Wednesday question and answer
where we open up with the 10
Commandments that God had written for
the whole world to keep. Brother Tanzel.
And God spake all these words saying,
I am the Lord thy God, which have
brought thee out of the land of Egypt,
out of the house of bondage.
Thou shalt have no other gods before me.
Thou shalt not make unto thee any graven
image, or any likeness of anything
that is in heaven above, or that is in
the earth beneath, or that is in the
water under the earth.
Thou shalt not bow down thyself to them,
nor serve them.
For I the Lord thy God am a jealous God,
visiting the iniquity of the fathers
upon the children
unto the third and fourth generation
of them that hate me, and showing mercy
unto thousands of them that love me, and
keep my commandments. Thou shalt not
take the name of the Lord thy God in
vain.
For the Lord will not hold him guiltless
that taketh his name in vain.
Remember the sabbath day, to keep it
holy.
Six days shalt thou labour, and do all
thy work:
but the seventh day
is the sabbath of the Lord thy God:
in it thou shalt not do any work, thou,
nor thy son, nor thy daughter,
thy manservant, nor thy maidservant, nor
thy cattle, nor thy stranger that is
within thy gates.
For six days the Lord made heaven and
earth, the sea, and all that in them is,
and rested the seventh day: wherefore
the Lord blessed the sabbath day, and
hallowed it.
Honour thy father and thy mother: that
thy days may be long upon the land which
the Lord thy God giveth thee. Thou shalt
not kill.
Thou shalt not commit adultery.
Thou shalt not steal.
Thou shalt not bear false witness
against thy neighbour.
Thou shalt not covet thy neighbour's
house. Thou shalt not covet thy
neighbour's wife, nor his manservant,
nor his maidservant, nor his ox, nor his
ass, nor any thing that is thy
neighbour. We read it Exodus 20:1-17.
May the Lord have a blessing to the
reading of his words. In Jesus' name we
pray.
Amen.
So here on question and answer, you can
ask us a question and we'll answer it
according to the King James Bible. And
if we cannot find the answer, we will
seek further counsel to bring you an
answer at a later time. The questions we
will not answer are the vague and the
long scripture questions as well as
questions of debate. We are not here to
debate, we are here to spread the true
gospel of Jesus. So please be as direct
as possible with your questions so we
can be as direct as possible with our
answers out of the King James Bible. No
other Bibles or books will be
acknowledged on this program. Also keep
in mind that this is a live stream, so
feel free to send in your questions that
pertain to everlasting life. We just
asking that you please keep them to a
two scripture maximum.
Well, let me introduce to you the family
that's on the panel this evening. We got
brother Dre.
Good evening.
Brother Julius. Good evening, everybody.
Brother Tanzel.
Good evening, everyone.
Sister Deborah.
Good evening.
Brother Sean.
Good evening. And
And we have the guest caller with us,
and I'm brother Cornell.
Sister Deborah, we want to begin with
our first question of the evening, and
we want to also state that Ruth is
David's great-grandmother.
Ruth is David's great-grandmother.
All right. There are several held over
questions that will be answered first
before getting into tonight's Q&A.
Onefer Thompson says, "My question is
about people that say they are black
Indians, and their ancestors were here
before the slave trade. Is it biblical
that Hebrew Israelites were here in
America before slavery?"
All right, dealing with the black
Indians and their ancestors, and the
guest caller will take it from there.
Well, the first thing is, you don't have
no proof of that.
But the second thing is, nobody pay
attention to what
the Bible say, that's going to happen to
Israel because we failed to keep God's
laws. So we just going to hit a few
We're going to hit a a few scriptures to
let you know
and uh uh uh
and this is the only reason. Otherwise,
we wouldn't even know that we was Hebrew
Israelites.
So there there black people all over the
world.
Yep.
And they and they are not all
Israelites. In fact, we wouldn't even
know that we was Israelites
period if we don't use the Bible.
So let's We're just going to hit a
couple places. Let's go into Deuteronomy
28th chapter.
And first we're going to read verse 64.
Deuteronomy 28,
verse 64.
And the Lord shall scatter thee among
all people,
from the one end of the earth even unto
the other.
And there thou shalt serve other gods,
which neither thou nor thy fathers have
known, even wood and stone.
The Lord is saying he's going to scatter
you. Then he's going to say you're going
to serve other gods. But skip down to
verse 68 and read that.
And the Lord shall bring thee into Egypt
again with ships, by the way whereof I
spake unto thee: thou shalt see it no
more again: and there ye shall be sold
unto your enemies for bondmen and
bondwomen, and no man shall buy you.
Now, the Lord just told us that he's
going to scatter us all over the world,
so bringing us into Egypt again by ships
is not talking about literally going
into Egypt. Hosea tell you that we ain't
going to go back down there no more.
But he but this represent
all these places that he's going to
scatter you to, it represent
uh uh uh uh
Egypt You know what that Egypt represent
the house of bondage.
So now,
he said that you're going to be when you
get there you're going to be sold as
male and female slaves,
and ain't nobody going to buy you out of
it.
The first thing is,
who was here that was sold as male and
female slaves?
Now skip down to uh uh
verse uh skip let's back up to verse 41
and read it.
Thou shalt beget sons and daughters, but
thou shalt not enjoy them; for they
shall go into captivity.
Now letting you know still they're going
to be going to slavery.
And the Lord gave us these signs among
other signs. But the big thing that he
gave us, nobody pays attention to.
And let's go let's look at the uh
Let's uh uh uh
Mhm.
See.
Where he says he's going to be a a a a a
a a sign and a wonder to you.
I think that's the
mhm
That's the Deuteronomy 28, right?
The Deuteronomy 28, but I'm trying to
look where he says this is going to be a
sign and a
>> 46. 46. What
46.
>> 46.
Go ahead.
And they shall be upon thee for a sign
and for a wonder,
and upon thy seed forever.
Now, these things that he said going to
be up on you as a sign and a wonder,
what's a sign? A sign identifies don't
it? Right.
Now, the only reason we know that we are
Israelites is because we are the only
people in this hemisphere that was
brought here as slaves.
And once we got here, we were sold as
male and female slaves.
And we can't enjoy we couldn't enjoy our
children because they were went into
captivity.
Another ship of the scripture tell you
going to be here the way in prison
houses.
So now,
if you get rid of the sign, what do we
have to identify that we are Hebrew
Israelites? Nothing. Nothing.
Yeah.
So these black Indians, whatever they
are,
I don't have a clue who they are, but I
know I had a old reader's digest. I
don't know where I could I tried to find
it, but I couldn't that said that the
Canaanites was
because the Canaanite was big travelers.
In fact, they found a plaque over here
that says to Bale, the God of the
Canaanites.
Mhm. Wow.
Mhm. But they didn't come here as
slaves. We are the only one in this
hemisphere that was sold as slaves.
Mhm. And all the rest of Israel that was
in all the other places was sold as
slaves. The Syrians took out nine
tribes, and the Babylonians took out the
three, and from then
we have been
gone from nation to nation, to
generation to generation as slaves.
So now,
people that say you got some black
Indians over here that was Hebrew
Israelites that came
early.
Ask them how did they come here?
That's all I have to say.
Yes, sir.
All right.
Thank you for that and hope that answers
your question as we continue to move on.
Moving on. Ninja Stringer says, "Paul in
1 Corinthians 7:19
and the entire book of Galatians
essentially is telling the Gentiles that
circumcision is nothing.
To just believe and have faith in Jesus.
Is this the Roman Catholic doctrine?"
All right, beginning with that 1
Corinthians 7:19,
Brother Dre, what you say?
I'd say that to say just believe and not
do, James let you know the devils
believe and they tremble. And don't you
know that faith without works is dead.
You got to do more than just believe,
but let's go
and read that uh 1 Corinthians 7. We
going to read verse 18. Start it read 18
and 19.
Go ahead.
>> any man called being circumcised?
Well, let him not become uncircumcised.
Is any called in uncircumcision?
Let him not be circumcised.
Circumcision is nothing.
And uncircumcision is nothing.
But the keeping of the commandments of
God. Yeah, circumcision is the keeping
of the commandments of God, but
uncircumcision is not. And if you get
circumcised, how can you become
uncircumcised?
So, we not talk we talking about
something a little bit deeper here, but
this is Paul talking. Skip down to verse
23. Go ahead.
Ye are bought with a price.
Be not ye the servants of men. Hey, you
bought with a price.
Be not the servants of men.
Now, let's go over and we going to read
uh
see what that price is. Let's go to uh 1
Corinthians 6 now. 1 Corinthians 6
and we going to read verses 19 and 20.
1 Corinthians 6:19 and 20. Go ahead.
What? Know ye not that your bodies
body is the temple of the Holy Ghost,
which is in you,
which you have of God, and ye are not
your own?
For ye are bought with a price.
Therefore, glorify God in your body and
in your spirit, which are God's.
>> So, whatever God tell you to do with
that body, you should do it. Now, let's
go over to Acts 20
and we going to read verse 28 there.
Acts 20:28.
Read it when you get there, brother.
Take heed therefore unto yourselves and
to all the flock, over the which the
Holy Ghost have made you overseers,
to feed the church of God, which he have
purchased with his own blood. That's
what you was bought with the blood of
Jesus.
That's right.
>> So, glorify God in your body, but let's
go over to Genesis 17 now.
Genesis 17 and pick it up at verse 9,
brother. Read it when you get there.
And God said unto Abraham, "Thou shalt
keep my covenant. Therefore, thou and
thy seed after thee in their generation.
Mhm. This is my covenant, which ye shall
keep between me and you.
And thy seed after thee, every man child
among you shall be circumcised. Now,
this is what God told Abraham.
And he said that this is the covenant
that you should keep, you and the
generations after you.
Go ahead.
And you shall circumcise the flesh of
your foreskin.
And this shall be a token of the
covenant betwixt me and you.
And he that is eight days old shall be
circumcised among you.
Every man child in your generation.
He that is born in the house or bought
with money of any stranger, which is not
of thy seed.
He that is born in thy house and he that
is bought with thy money
must needs be circumcised.
And my covenant shall be in your flesh
for an everlasting covenant. Notice this
that he doubled down on he that is born
in the house and bought with money
because you bought with a price.
And
he said you must needs be circumcised,
whether you be
uh one that's born in the house, bought
with money of any stranger. That is
including all people. Go ahead, brother.
And the uncircumcised man child whose
flesh of his foreskin is not
circumcised,
that soul shall be cut off from my from
his people.
He have broken my covenant.
And that is what God said because when
you read verse 9, it says God said this.
And Paul said,
"Don't be looking at man. You follow
what God say." One more place. Let's go
to
uh Ezekiel 44. This is in the kingdom.
This is in Christ's kingdom. Ezekiel 44
and I want you to pick it up at verse 1
and 2.
Go ahead when you get there.
Then brought me back the way of the gate
of the outward sanctuary, which looked
toward the east, and it was shut.
Then said the Lord unto me, "This gate
shall be shut.
It shall not be open, and no man shall
enter in by it,
because the Lord, the God of Israel,
have entered in by it. Therefore, it
shall be shut." So, this is for a time
to come. Now, let's look at what's
happening during this time. Verse 6,
brother. Go ahead.
And thou shalt say to the rebellious,
"Even to the house of Israel,
thus saith the Lord God, O ye house of
Israel, let it suffice you of all your
abomination
in that ye have brought into my
sanctuary strangers,
uncircumcised in heart and uncircumcised
in flesh,
to be in my sanctuary.
That covers both, uncircumcised in heart
and uncircumcised in flesh. That's
right. Go ahead.
To be in my sanctuary to pollute it,
even my house.
When ye offer my bread, the fat and the
blood, they have broken my covenant
because of all your abomination.
So, hey, again, when you go back to that
1 Corinthians 7,
Paul said something here that I want you
to pay attention to, real close in verse
23.
He said, "You are bought with a price.
Be not ye servants of men.
Serve God." This is the word of God
here.
Had Look, must needs be circumcised is
what God say.
Just do it.
Yeah. Just do it.
That's all I got if anybody would like
to add.
Yeah, you should you should have read
that in 8 verse in
uh
Ezekiel 44.
Yes, sir. Let's read that.
Ezekiel 44:1-9. Read that, brother.
Thus saith the Lord God, "No stranger,
uncircumcised in heart, nor
uncircumcised in flesh, shall enter in
into my sanctuary of any stranger that
is among the children of Israel."
And I think that God's word supersedes
anything that man will say.
That's right.
>> Thus saith the Lord God. Thank you, Gus
Carlton.
That's all I got.
Yes, sir.
All right. We hope that that answers
your question as we move on to our next
one.
Moving on. Angela Burns asks, "How do
you explain to family that ask questions
about when you die, you go to heaven and
use this verse, 'Absent from the body,
present with the Lord' and 2 Corinthians
15:52
is given. I tell them about 2
Corinthians 5:8."
All right, so Brother Julius need a
little light on that question there.
Okay, we got to spend some time with
this real quick and quickly as possible.
First of all, let's make a correction to
the scripture that you posted. There is
no 2 Corinthians 15:52.
You mean 1 1 Corinthians 15:52. So,
let's answer the last question first.
How do you explain uh when your family
says, "Absent from the body, present
with the Lord"?
You answer them with the word of God,
with the book. You have to make them
have their own Bibles so they can read
it for themselves.
And then, let's answer the last question
first.
Absent from the body, present with the
Lord. Let's see if Paul said that
exactly.
Let's go to 2
Let's go to second Corinthians.
The fifth chapter, Tenzel.
Okay. Second [clears throat] Corinthians
chapter five.
Okay.
Because I can't tell you how many times
I've heard that after from the body
present with the Lord. I agree with
that, but when?
And how?
Second Corinthians five, let's pick this
up read verses one and two cuz this is
what they try to use also. Go ahead, T.
For we know that if our earthly house of
this tabernacle were dissolved, we have
a building of God, an house not made
with hands, eternal in the heavens.
Now, that body, that's that spiritual
body that's going to come from heaven
that's being prepared. Go ahead, verse
two.
For in this we groan, earnestly desiring
to be clothed upon with our house which
is from heaven. Not that you're going to
get it.
Not that you're going up there to get
it. Skip down, T, to verse four and read
it.
For we that are in this tabernacle do
groan,
being burdened, not for that we would be
unclothed, but clothed upon that
mortality might be swallowed up of life.
Now, underline and highlight that part
that mortality must be swallowed up of
life, which is immortality or eternal
life. Skip down to verse eight and nine.
Go ahead, brother.
We are confident, I say, and willing
rather to be absent from the body and to
And willing what?
to be absent from the body. Read it
again, Tenzel.
We are confident,
I say, and willing rather to be absent
from the body,
and to be present with the Lord. See,
people take that and they miss the word
rather,
which means they prefer.
That's what rather means. I prefer. We
are Paul said, we are confident, I say,
and willing rather to be absent from the
body. He didn't say absent from the body
present with the Lord. I would rather be
absent from the body and present with
the Lord. That's what Paul said. That is
a direct quotation. Read verse nine so
we can move on.
Wherefore we labor that whether present
or absent, we may be accepted of him.
And that's where your mindset should be.
That's what we're working on, salvation.
In your mind, that's this That's where
it should be. Now,
they say
at the beginning of the question, how do
you explain the family that ask
questions about when you die, you go to
heaven. Let's deal with that.
Cuz Paul didn't go to heaven. Nobody's
going to heaven.
Let's go to the book. Let's go to the
book, Tenzel. Let's go to Genesis and
this is how you answer people, sisters
and brothers, with the Bible. Genesis
chapter two and verse seven. Where did
man come from? Where did God get man
from?
Let's see if you came from heaven. Go
ahead.
And the Lord God formed man of the dust
of the ground, and breathed into his
nostrils the breath of life, and man
became a living soul. So, God formed
this body
from the dust of the ground, Adam, first
man Adam, and then put the breath in his
nostrils.
Now, let's see what happens when let's
reverse it.
Let's reverse it, sisters and brothers,
and let's
go to Psalm 104.
Take the book and make them read the
book. Psalm 104.
And when you get it, my brother, read
verse 28 and 29. Go ahead.
That thou givest them they
gather.
Thou openest thine hand, and they are
filled with good.
Go ahead. Thou hidest thy face, they are
troubled. Yes. Thou takest away their
breath, and they die.
They return to their dust. No.
You go to heaven.
They return to their dust. Just like the
book said. Let's prove that. Back to
Genesis the third chapter.
Man sinned.
And Adam sinned and brought death on us,
and let's look at what happens. Genesis
three and just verse 19. What happens,
brother?
In the sweat of thy face thou shalt eat
bread, till thou return unto the ground.
Uh-huh. Until you what?
Till thou return unto the ground. So,
now we read in Genesis 2:7, he got man
from the ground, put the breath in him.
We read Psalm 104 that you take away the
breath, the body go back to the ground.
Then we got a third witness that says
right here in 19, until you return out
of the ground. Go ahead and read.
For out of it was thou taken, for dust
thou art, and to and unto dust shalt
thou return. Now, let's go to quickly to
John, Saint John the third chapter. I
got one place after this.
John the third chapter. We're going to
put Jesus on the witness stand.
And it should be written in red in your
Bible. John chapter three verses 12 and
13. You go to church and they don't read
this to you. You get preached to, but
nobody's reading. Go ahead and read.
John
>> If I have
Go ahead and Go ahead and read.
If I have told you earthly things, and
ye believe not,
how shall ye believe if I tell you of
heavenly things? Yes. And no man have
ascended up to heaven, And no man, no
man
has ascended into the heavens. Go ahead.
But he that came down from heaven,
Uh-huh. even the Son of man, which is in
heaven. That's the third heaven. That's
why Jesus got a right to go back and sit
up on the right hand of the Father
because he came from heaven. Now,
let's go to our last place. Saint John 6
and 63.
Saint John 6, I'm sorry. Saint John the
sixth chapter. And we're going to pick
this up at 38 to 40.
Saint John 6.
Saint John
chapter six. This is Jesus should be
written in red in your Bible again if
you got a red letter Bible, and pick it
up at 38 to 40. This is why he told you
you return to the ground.
Go ahead.
For I came down from heaven,
not to do my own will, but the will of
him that sent me. Go ahead. And this is
the Father's will which have sent me,
that of all which he have given me, I
should lose nothing,
but should raise it up again at the last
day. You can't be up in heaven and then
he got to raise you. That's number one.
Continue. And this is the will of him
that sent me,
that everyone which seeth the Son,
and believeth on him,
may have everlasting life.
And I will raise him up at the last day.
You can't go to heaven and he got to
raise you up at the last day. That's
trumpet number seven. Skip down to verse
44. That's two times I'm going to raise
you up. Go ahead.
No man can come to me, except the Father
which have sent me draw him.
And I will raise him up
at the last day. That's why you have a
funeral. That's why they dig the hole,
lower you into it because the grave is a
holding place for the dead until a
resurrection. One more, verse 54 and
we're done.
Whoso eateth my flesh, and drinketh my
blood, Yes.
>> hath eternal life. Yes. And I will raise
him up
at the last day.
And on your own you can read Second
Corinthians First Corinthians the 15th
chapter, he will tell you that this
mortal must put on immortality.
And he's going to change you at the last
trumpet. That is trumpet number seven,
and then this mortal going to change to
immortality.
Sisters and brothers, so you take the
book and let the book do the talking.
Right.
>> They cannot, unless you're going to call
God a liar. He told you no man has
ascended into heaven except he that came
down, and I'm going to raise you up at
the last
day. So, where are the dead? In the
grave until a resurrection. That's all I
got, Cornelius.
All right. Thank you for that, brother.
Can we
>> Yes, caller.
I can throw something in on the first
part of this.
People, you know, like Paul said,
he would rather be absent from the body
and present with the Lord. You
understand?
Yeah. But people really understand
uh uh uh
what
Paul is doing, you know, he but he can't
be. I myself, I would rather be absent
from the body
and present with the Lord. But what
body?
>> I'mma show you what body I want to be
absent from.
Let's go into First Corinthians 15th
chapter,
and start reading at verse 49.
And as we have borne the image of the
earthly, we shall also bear the image of
the heavenly.
You know, we are bearing the image of
the earthly right now. We flesh and
blood. Right.
>> Go ahead.
Now, this I say, brethren, that flesh
and blood cannot inherit the kingdom of
God.
Neither do corruption inherit
incorruption.
You know, this is the Father's kingdom.
Now, if you want to be in the Father's
kingdom
and you're flesh and blood,
you can't go there, can you? No, sir.
>> No.
What have to happen? Keep reading.
Behold, I show you a mystery.
We shall not all sleep, but we shall all
be changed.
Uh-huh. In a moment,
in the twinkling of an eye,
at the last trump. For the trumpet shall
sound and the dead shall be raised
incorruptible, and we shall be changed.
Go ahead.
For this corruptible must put on
incorruption.
And this mort- mortal must put on
immortality.
Now, so this what it's all about. Then
you will have a spirit body.
Right. Yes.
So, now, I'd rather be absent from this
body
and present with the Lord.
That mean that I'm in the Father's
kingdom. Mhm.
>> cannot
I cannot go into the Father's kingdom
in this flesh and blood body. No, sir.
>> to be absent.
It have to be changed to a spirit body.
That's all I want to say.
Mhm.
>> Thank you. All right.
Thank you for that and we hope that that
answered your question as you take those
scriptures to your family because we
understand that a whole doctrine has
been taught on going to heaven, which is
simply not true.
All right. We're going to move on to our
next question.
Next question. Charles Toomer asks, "Is
it not resting
if
traveling on the Sabbath to see family,
but listening to service while driving?"
Well, yeah, that could still be
considered resting as long as you are
you are prepared for it and you are
keeping the Sabbath day.
You still can keep the Sabbath day while
you're on the road.
We have brothers that travel all the
time, be it by car, van, or airplane.
And you can still keep the Sabbath.
Just don't be blazing down the highway
listening to Earth, Wind, and Fire. Make
sure that you keep the Sabbath like you
would
any other day. But let's go into Isaiah
58, Brother Tenzel, and show how the
Sabbath have to be kept cuz it's still a
holy day. And you want to treat it holy
and give God all the respect and
reverence
that he deserve. Isaiah 58 and 13. Cuz
you can still do this while you're
traveling, while you're in your car.
Just plan, pack your lunch, and hey, go
ahead, my brother, read.
If thou turn away thy foot from the
Sabbath,
from doing thy pleasure on my holy day,
and call the Sabbath a delight,
the holy of the Lord honorable,
and shall honor him, not doing thy own
ways, nor finding thy own pleasure, nor
speaking
>> [clears throat]
>> thy own words.
Then shall thou delight thyself in the
Lord.
And I will cause thee to ride upon the
high places of the earth, and feed thee
with the heritage of Jacob, thy father.
For the mouth of the Lord have spoken
it. Yeah, so
yeah, as long as you keep the Sabbath
honorable and keep it holy and a delight
unto the Lord, you can do that while
you're on the road or by plane or
however you might be traveling, but make
sure you keep the Lord's Sabbath day and
it could still be considered a day of
resting for you.
Brother Cornell, let me let me throw
something in there, brother. We are
traveling when we do travel on the
Lord's Sabbath day, we are taking care
of his business.
We're taking care of the Lord's business
and Jesus traveled on the Sabbath day
and took care of the Lord's business.
That's all I got.
Yeah. Yeah, so yeah, that is one way and
like they say, too, if they're going to
see their family, still keep the Sabbath
day, honor him. Mhm. The Lord can always
pour out a blessing. All right.
Thank you for that add-on as we move on
to our next question.
Moving on. This comment might be funny
says, "I have a question about the lunar
calendar. Is there a scripture that
instruct us to add a lunar cycle for
realignment every 3 years? And if there
is in a specific scripture, how do we
know that we have to do that?"
All right. So, this caller, this
question is in need of some light
regarding the lunar calendar.
Well, the first thing is this comment is
not funny.
And the reason we use it is because God
told us.
First, let's go into Genesis, the first
chapter. Read verses 14
through 16.
Genesis 1.
Yep.
14.
And God said, "Let there be lights in
the firmament of the heaven to divide
the day from the night.
And let them be for signs, and for
seasons, and for days and years.
And let them be for lights in the
firmament of the heaven to give light
upon the earth. And it was so.
And God made two great lights.
The greater light to rule the day, and
the lesser light to rule the night. And
he made the stars also.
So, now, like you said in the 14th
verse,
let them be for signs.
And read again. Just read that one verse
again and then pay attention to what it
say.
Let them be for what now?
And God said, "Let there be lights in
the firmament of the heaven to divide
the day from the night.
And let them be for signs, and for
seasons, and for days and years.
[snorts]
Now, the Lord told us, now these lights
we talking about the the the
the sun and the moon and the stars. But
the big thing is the sun and the moon.
The Lord said, "Let them be for signs."
Right.
You know, in other words,
uh
it didn't say that we are going to
operate them. It's saying that we going
to operate according to them.
So, now, if they're the one that's going
to set going to be a sign, they're the
one that's going to set the
the months and the years,
then they will dictate our action.
But what you have to understand is
is doing the
a year,
every year,
the year because the year is 365 days,
and when you get the rotation of the
moon, sometimes it is
and 355 days. So, in a year's time, it
always They always come.
You know, the I'm talking about the
the collective
days of the
of the year,
they always come
every year.
There's extra 10 to 11 days added to the
year.
Now,
when you do that every 3 years, what
happen is you have added a whole month
worth of days.
So, you have to make an adjustment.
We didn't make the moon and the stars do
that. That's the way they travel. So,
you have to make an adjustment.
Otherwise, if you otherwise, you're
going to have
13 months. And then if you don't make
the adjustment,
the following year after these 3 years,
the year will start a month early.
And if you go another 3 years and don't
make the adjustment to cover these
additional
10 11 days a year,
you're going to back up another month.
So, you saying it's
and and
March.
Then if you don't make the adjustment,
your next uh
year is going to start in February.
And if you still don't make an
adjustment, it's going to start in
January. You're going to keep backing up
and be around August somewhere.
Throw it all off.
That's That's right. And that's why
That's why you have to make this
realignment every 3 years because
collectively, every year, we pick up
10 to 11 days. And in 3 years, you done
picked up a whole month.
So, if you don't make the adjustment,
if you don't realign it,
by you going to be keeping the Passover
in August.
Mhm.
So, the sun and the moon
is the one that dictates this.
It's all that simple.
Mhm. That's all I have to say. And and
that And the scripture for it, we just
read it.
Read it one more time, that 14th verse.
And God said, "Let there be lights in
the firmament of the heaven to divide
the day from the night.
And let them be for signs, and for
seasons, and for days and years.
So, that's what they're for. They're for
signs, and they're for seasons, and
they're for days and the
That's every month
starts with the new moon. That's where
the month That's where That's where the
month come from.
But collectively
in these 12 months
you're going to pick up 10-11 days.
Another year, 10-11 days.
Another year, 10-11 days. Doing 3 years
you do that, you don't add another
month. So, if you don't make the
adjustment
the next year is going to start a month
early. And on and on and on and on. Like
I said, you'll be keeping Passover in
August. That's all I have to say.
All right.
Thank you for that.
Hopefully good light answered your
question as we move on to our next
question.
Next one, Keanna Russell asked, is
cremation a sin?
Uh nope.
Cremation is not a sin.
Sin is the transgression of the law. But
let's go into uh 1 Samuel
and let's see what happened to
the first king of Israel here.
Let's see what happened to him and his
sons. 1 Samuel 31.
1 Samuel 31, brother, and let's pick it
up at that verse six and then we go skip
down.
1 Samuel 31 and 6. Go ahead.
So, Saul died, and his three sons, and
his armor bearer, and all his men, the
same day together.
So, Saul and his three sons all died.
This was the first king of Israel.
And even God appointed him that spot.
Skip down to verse 8. Go ahead.
And it came to pass on the morrow, when
the Philistines came to strip the slain,
they found Saul and his three sons
fallen in Mount Gilboa.
Mhm. And they cut off his head and
stripped off his armor, and sent into
the land of the Philistines round about
to publish it in the house of their
idols and among the people.
Mhm.
And they put his armor in the house of
Ashteroth, and they fastened his body to
the wall of Beth-shan.
And let's see what happened when the
inhabitants of Jabesh Gilead
found out about it. Go ahead.
And when they that happened of Jabesh
Gilead heard of that which the
Philistine had done to Saul, all the
valiant men arose, and went all night,
and took the body of Saul,
and the bodies of his sons from the wall
of Beth-shan,
and came to Jabesh, and burnt them
there.
Yeah, all the valiant men came and they
took them
uh Saul and his three sons' bodies, and
they burnt them there. Verse 13.
And they took their bones, and buried
them under a tree at Jabesh,
and fasted 7 days. So, they burnt their
bodies there,
and that's it's the same thing that they
do creation cremation with people
nowadays. And um
Brother Dre, it's very popular, isn't
it?
Yeah, um a lot of I I read a story about
them taking 10 bodies and putting it
into a
cremation and just
taking the ashes and giving them the
loved ones, but they didn't know
whose ashes they were, you know?
Creamated all together.
Yeah. Yeah. And we know, Brother Dre,
that God know.
Yeah. And he he can put everybody back
together cuz hey, he formed man out of
the dust of the ground. That's right.
So, he'll be able to do that again with
no problem. But no, cremation is not a
sin. That is your choice for your family
or your loved ones. And that's all I
got.
And we hope that that answered your
question as we continue to move on with
the time check.
The time is 8:14. Moving on, Charles
Toomer asked, are we praying to the
Father or Jesus?
Hey Dre, so when we pray, are we praying
to the Father or Jesus?
Pray to the Father in Jesus' name, but
let's go
>> Amen. to uh
John the 15th chapter
and let's read verse 16.
John 15 and verse 16.
Go ahead when you get it, Tenzel.
Ye have not chosen me, but I have chosen
you, and ordained you, that you should
go and bring forth fruit,
and that your fruit should remain,
for that whatsoever ye shall ask of the
Father in my name,
he may give it you. Yeah, you asking the
Father in Jesus' name.
And he will give it you. Let's go to uh
Matthew 6
and read one verse, verse 9. Matthew 6
and 9.
Go ahead.
After this manner therefore pray.
Our Father which art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name. That's right. Now,
why do you pray to the Father in Jesus'
name? Let's go to
uh Romans 8 and read verse 34.
Why you do this?
Romans 8 and 34. Go ahead when you get
it, brother.
Who is he that condemneth?
It is Christ that died?
Yea, rather, that is risen again,
who is even at the right hand of God,
who also maketh intercession for us.
That's right. He is the intercessor for
us.
Like the high priest, he intercedes for
us. One last place, Hebrews 7 verse 25.
Hebrews 7 and 25. Go ahead, brother,
when you get it.
Wherefore he is able also to save them
to the uttermost
that come unto God by him,
seeing he ever liveth to make
intercession for them.
He is our intercessor.
He intercedes to the Father, and that is
why we pray to the Father in Jesus'
name. That's all I got.
All right. Thank you for that, brother.
And that is a good thing to know.
All right. Let's move on to our next
question.
Next one, Deborah Wilder uh wants you to
explain Jeremiah 33 verse 3 and Hosea 12
verse 10. What is the difference between
enigmas and parables?
All right. In those two verses, Jeremiah
33 and 3, Hosea 12 and 10, what is the
difference between the two?
Brother Julius.
Mute.
>> [clears throat]
>> Go to Jeremiah 33 and 3 and read that,
Tenzel.
Call upon me, and I will answer thee,
and show
and show thee great and mighty things,
which thou knowest not.
Okay.
Pray unto me or call unto me, and I will
answer thee, and show thee great and
mighty things, which thou knowest not.
Let's go to Hosea 12
and read the 10th verse.
I have also spoken by the prophets, and
have multiplied visions,
and used similitudes by the ministry of
the prophets.
Now, the question is
uh what is the difference between What
is it, Deborah?
What is the difference between enigmas
and parables?
Enigma is
uh an enigma is like a puzzle or
something that's puzzling.
Uh a parable is a earthly story with a
spiritual meaning.
So, now, the Lord told you, call upon
me. I mean
people
I don't know if they get this stuff from
seminary school, but they throw these
things in there have nothing to do with
either one of The Lord said, call pray
unto me and I'm going to show you
things. But then he tell you at verse 2
and then Hosea 12, I have also spoken by
prophets, and have multiplied visions,
and used similitudes by the ministry of
the prophets.
It's nothing mysterious. You just got to
understand how the Lord works. He give
you similitudes. He gave you a beautiful
similitude in the book of Daniel, the
second chapter. The similitude of four
beasts, the lion, Babylon, the bear,
Medo-Persian, the goat, Greece, and then
he gave you the wild and the great
terrible beast, which is the Roman
Empire.
These are scriptures and prophecies.
That's why I said, I have spoken by the
prophets, and have multiplied visions.
So, they What the prophet do is they
prophesy that which is written, that
which is future.
So, people don't make it make the word
of God what we call spookarize it and
make it mystery and use words like
enigmas, which is puzzlings, and the
Lord said, I have never hidden anything
from you, Israel.
So, we just got to stick with the book
and don't
make the word of God mysterious like
it's not understandable. That's what
people do.
So, it nothing to do with enigmas. Has
everything to do with understanding. I
hope that helped, Cornell.
Indeed it did, brother.
Whosoever read, let them understand.
All right. We're going to move on to our
next question.
Next question. Latrice Stringer says,
"How can I witness to my family about my
new revelations
that I now follow the way, feasts,
commandments, and also differentiate
between
differentiate
to them the
the
to them
the Jesus, the Baptist
worship, and Jesus who rose on Sabbath.
Help."
All right.
Cornell, the she's trying to ask how do
she differentiate between the Jesus of
the Bible and the Jesus of and and and
what you call the Baptist Church. That's
what she's really saying.
You know, first of all,
whoever asking the question, you got to
have a solid understanding of the word
of God. So, you can prove these things
and know where to go and make them
challenge what they have traditionally
been taught.
This is what
you have to understand. Let's go to 2
Corinthians, the 11th chapter. See,
like I said earlier, you go to church
all your life and you get preached away
from the truth.
Right.
But,
you would never hear the people uh read
this right here.
2 Corinthians, the 11th chapter, 2
Corinthians, read verse 3 and 4. This is
what the people won't read.
2 Corinthians 11:3 and 4. Go ahead.
But, I fear lest by any means, as the
serpent beguiled Eve through his
subtlety, so your minds should be
corrupted from the simplicity that is in
Christ. Go ahead. For if he that cometh
preacheth another Jesus, Oh, Paul is
warning you about the coming of the
preaching of another Jesus. Go ahead.
whom we have not preached,
or if you receive another spirit, which
you have not received, or another
gospel,
which you have not accepted, you might
well bear with them. That means you
contend with them. You challenge them.
Challenge them. Skip all the way over to
verse 13, 13 to 15. This is what the
world has been deceived by. Go ahead.
For such are false apostles,
deceitful workers,
transforming themselves into the
apostles of Christ.
Re- Remember that. I like that.
Transforming themselves into the
apostles of Christ. Go ahead.
And no marvel,
for Satan himself is transformed into an
angel of light. Go ahead. Therefore, it
is no great thing if his ministers also
be transformed as the ministers of
righteousness,
whose end shall be according to their
works. You mean say the devil got a
church and Satan the devil say the devil
got ministers? Yes.
Let me show you our last place. Yes.
Matthew, the 24th chapter. Remember,
false apostles, deceitful workers
transformed themselves into the apostles
of Christ. Look what Jesus said in
Matthew, the 24th chapter, and read
verse 4 and 5.
And Jesus answered and said unto them,
"Take heed that no man deceive you.
For many shall come in my name, saying,
'I am Christ.' Now,
go ahead.
And shall deceive many." Because they
have a transformed themselves. Satan
works through people. He got ministers.
He had a day. He has church. He has
churches. So, these ministers stand
before you and they use the name of
Jesus, but they deceive you in that
name.
Skip down to verse 13.
Go ahead.
But, he that shall endure unto the end,
the same shall be saved. But, they tell
you, Satan ministers tell you when you
say the sinner's prayer, now you saved
already. Right. They have deceived you
in the name of Jesus. But, they don't
read. So, this is what you got to
understand. You got to know where to go
in the Bible to answer these questions.
And then,
read it to them. Make them read it. And
then, ask them questions such as, "Why
do you go to church on Sunday? Right.
Why do you believe that Jesus died on
Good Friday and rose Sunday morning? And
the book tell you in Matthew, 12th
chapter, he going he going to give you
the sign of the prophet Jonas.
You can't get three days from Friday to
Sunday.
And he told you in in Daniel that
Messiah ben shall be killed in the midst
of the week. So, you have to make people
challenge what they have traditionally
been taught, and they cannot. That's all
I got, Cornell. Anybody want to add to
that?
All right. Thank you for that, brother.
Hope that answered their question, and
sister, continue to let your light
shine. Yes, ma'am.
All right. So, let's move on to our next
question.
Moving on. Nate Hudson asks, "When you
get married, are we to honor our in-laws
as we honor our own parents?"
What about this honoring of the in-laws
when you get married, brother Dre? What
you say?
I don't think anything is wrong with
honoring your parents.
Right.
>> And your your parent your your
mother-in-law and father-in-law.
I think it's a good thing. Uh
you married. You one. But, let's go to
uh Romans, the 12th chapter. Let's see
what the Bible say.
Romans 12 and read verse 18.
Romans 12 and 18. Go ahead, brother.
If it be possible, as much as lieth in
you, live peaceably with all men. So,
hey, live peaceably with all.
You know, I know that in Matthew 10, it
talks about that the Lord didn't come to
send peace, but a sword. Right. But,
let's go and read that right quick.
Let's go to Matthew 10 and read verse
35.
Go ahead when you get there, brother.
For I am
For I am come to set a man at variance
against his father,
and the daughter against her mother, and
the daughter-in-law against her
mother-in-law.
Go ahead.
>> And a man's foes shall be they of his
own household.
So, sometimes it's like that because you
not able to get along with them. They
might have some different views, but
that doesn't mean you can't honor them
and show them respect and regard.
So,
uh let's let's look at one instance of
that. Let's go to Ruth, the first
chapter. Ruth, the first chapter.
Let's see what Ruth say.
Because Ruth had
Naomi was her mother-in-law.
And she lost her husband.
And this is what Ruth with Naomi said.
Let's go to Ruth 1,
start at verse 15. Go ahead, brother.
Yeah, it'll be it'll be that Joshua,
Judges, and then you have the book of
Ruth.
Joshua, Judges, and then Ruth.
Yep. When you get there, read verses 1 I
mean, start at verse 15.
Chapter 1.
And she said, "Behold, thy sister-in-law
is gone back unto her people,
and unto her god. Return thou after thy
sister-in-law."
So, she said, "Hey,
you know, my my son is gone. I'm not
going to have another one. By the time I
have them, you be too old to deal with
them. So,
go on with your sister." But, Ruth say,
"Go ahead."
And Ruth said, "Entreat me not to leave
thee,
or to return from following after thee.
For whither thou goest, I will go.
And where thou lodgest, I will lodge.
And thy people shall be my people, and
thy god my god.
Go ahead. So, where thou diest, will I
die, and there will I be buried. The
Lord do so to me, and more also, if
aught but death part thee and me." Go
ahead. One more verse. And when she saw
that she was steadfastly minded to go
with her,
then she left speaking unto her.
That's right. So, Naomi lost her
husband. She lost her sons.
But, she Ruth entreated her.
That was her mother-in-law, and she
showed honor and respect for her
mother-in-law. And I think we should
honor
uh mother and father-in-laws.
That's all I got.
Yeah. It's right, Dre.
>> They are still an extension. Whether you
agree with them or not, they still an
extension of your family. That's right.
You don't agree with your own family all
the time. But, you still got to honor
them.
Yeah. You know.
Yeah. Kind of
kind of like a little package deal. Yes,
sir. All comes together.
Yes, sir.
All right. Hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next one.
Next one, Mel Natural Journey asks,
"What should we do if we experience any
paranormal activity?"
What do you do if you experience that
paranormal activity going on, brother
Julius? Well, we have a lot of that in
the Bible, what you call dealing with
the supernatural. Right.
>> You know, and and and different strange
phenomena, certain things that are
unexplained that you don't understand. I
would say first thing,
because some things are very
frightening.
Uh but you pray, if you can pray,
try your best not to remain calm,
and you pray to God, and it it depend on
what the paranormal activity is.
Let me give you a example of this right
here.
Job chapter 4,
Tenzel.
Cuz we're talking about paranormal
activity, what man calls dealing with
the supernatural.
The Bible is dealing full of
dealing with spirits.
Uh
clean and unclean angels.
Job chapter 4, and pick it up at verse
1. This is one of Job's friends. Go
ahead. Verse 1, and then we'll skip. Go
ahead, my brother.
Then Eliphaz the Temanite answered and
said, Skip down to verse 12. This is
Job's friend, Eliphaz. Go ahead.
Now a thing was secretly brought to me,
and my ear received a little thereof.
Uh-huh. In thoughts from the vision of
the night,
when deep sleep falleth upon men,
What happened?
Fear came upon me and trembling, Uh-huh.
>> which made all my bones to shake. What
happened? Then a spirit passed before my
face.
The hair of my flesh stood up. Yes.
It stood still,
but I could not discern the form
thereof. Yes.
An image was before my eyes. Yes.
>> silence.
And I heard a voice saying, Yes.
"Shall mortal man be more just than God?
Shall a man be more
pure than his maker?"
And that's what Eliphaz learned from
that paranormal activity, from that
spirit.
Uh the message that was really for Job.
Came through Eliphaz, but the bottom
line is we the Bible is full of these
kind of things right here. Right.
>> So,
uh understand, and sometimes things
happen to give you understanding. The
Lord talked to you in your sleep, upon
your bed, sometimes in a vision. Right.
So, you know, those that's just one of
the examples. Another example, you could
read Acts the second chapter, how I'm
sorry, how um
the spirit came upon Cornelius.
You know, and it was for his good and
his family's good. So, a lot of it come
with understanding, and it depend on
what the activity is. That's the best I
can do with that.
All right, thank you for that. Hope that
answered their question. Next question.
Next one, Investment Fund says, "I read
the scripture when the Lord told us we
are his witnesses, but I overheard
someone say he was talking about that
with the 12 disciples.
So, does that scripture cover Israel as
a whole?
Isaiah 43 verse 10 is given."
All right. Well, the Lord is talking
about the witnesses, and they want to
start off at that Isaiah 43 and 10.
And the guest caller will take it from
there.
Isaiah 43 and verse 10.
"Ye are my witnesses, saith the Lord,
and my servants whom I have chosen,
that ye may know and believe me,
and understand that I am he.
Before me there was no God formed.
Neither Neither shall there be after
me."
So, yes, that was talking about the
whole nation of Israel.
Skip down.
And
read verse
21 in that same chapter.
Verse 21?
Mhm.
>> Yep. "This people have I formed for
myself.
They shall show forth my praise."
Now, this people is talking about
Israel.
This people, Israel, he said, "I formed
for myself. They shall show forth my
praise."
Israel.
Now, let's go to Romans the third
chapter. Read verses 1 and 2.
"What What advantage then hath the Jew?
Or what profit is there of circumcision?
Much every way, chiefly, because that
unto them were committed the oracles of
God."
And what is oracles of God?
Answers. Answers.
What is it? Those are the words, isn't
that correct?
That's right.
So, now,
that's talking Israel.
And let's go into
Romans the ninth chapter chapter, and
start reading at verse one.
Romans 9
and verse
one.
"I say the truth in Christ.
I say the truth in Christ.
I lie not.
My conscience also beareth me witness in
the Holy Ghost,
that I have great heaviness and
continual sorrow in my heart.
For I could wish that myself were
accursed from Christ for my brethren,
my kinsmen according to the flesh,
who are Israelites,
to whom pertaineth the adoption, and the
glory,
and the covenants, and the giving of the
law,
and the service of God, and the
promises."
So, now,
read the next one.
"Whose are the fathers, and of whom as
concerning the flesh Christ came,
who is over all, God blessed forever.
Amen." So, now,
that's why Jesus had to come as an
Israelite.
Because Israel is the one
that represent Jesus. Israel is
Jehovah's witness.
And if you going to get salvation, you
got to go through Israel.
Right.
>> Mhm.
That speaks Jesus. So, let's go one last
place. St. John, the fourth chapter.
And we're going to start reading
at verse 19.
"The woman said unto him,
'Sir, I perceive that thou art a
prophet.
Our fathers worshipped in this mountain,
and ye say that in Jerusalem is this
place where men ought to worship.'
But Jesus said unto her,
'Woman, believe me,
the hour cometh,
when ye shall neither in this mountain,
nor yet at Jerusalem, worship the
Father.
Ye worship ye know not what.
We know we worship,
for salvation is of the Jews."
Now, look, if you don't go through
Israel, according to what Jesus said, do
you get salvation? Nope. Nope.
So, Israel
is the Lord is Jehovah's witnesses.
You got these Gentiles starting this
organization, got brothers and sisters
out in the streets talking about
Jehovah's witnesses. Uh-uh, he said he
formed us to show forth his praise.
Right.
>> His answers,
and which is his answers, is in our
hand.
So, we're the ones that
I could say in Romans the ninth chapter.
We're the ones that uh preaches the word
of God. We're the ones that show forth
his praise. We're the ones that teach
the law.
And if we don't get it through Israel,
you don't get it.
So, yeah,
we are
the Lord's witnesses. That's talking
about Israel.
Mhm.
Physical.
Yeah.
Don't have to say.
Yes, sir. Indeed.
Come on, wake up Israel.
The world needs it.
All right. We're going to move on to our
next question with a time check.
Yes, the time is 8:39. Bonnie Henderson
asked for you to explain Revelation 17
verses 10 and 11. Let's go there,
Tenzel, to Revelation 17
and then pick up that verse 10 and 11.
And the guest caller will take it from
there.
All right.
Revelation 17 and 10.
"And there are seven kings. Five are
fallen, and one is. And the other is not
yet come. And when he cometh, he must
continue a short space.
And the beast that was and is not
even he is the eighth and is of the
seven and goeth into perdition.
Okay, that's something about the
the the beast
uh uh uh uh
the the eighth. First thing is you had
the uh
seven men
starting with Babylon
Nebuchadnezzar
that that that ruled over this Gentile
dynasty because the times of the
Gentiles started with Nebuchadnezzar.
Okay, Nebuchadnezzar's one head
Medo-Persian, that's two.
Then you got the Greeks, that was four.
After Alexander the Great died, which
makes it six. Then you had the Roman
head, which is seven.
But when it comes down to these these
seven uh uh
uh uh
And then it went and said, "This is the
one that have wisdom."
So you had this uh you saw this beast
with with seven uh seven horns. Five are
fallen, one is, and one is to come.
Those horns represent the men that tried
to restore the
Roman Empire.
Remember when you saw the Roman Empire,
the beast had seven heads and 10 horns.
So these are the ones that but uh uh
but these but this head these 10 horns
represent uh these seven horns
represent the seven men that tried to
restore
the Holy Roman Empire.
The first one was Justinian.
The second one was Charlemagne.
Third one was Otto the Great.
The fourth one was Charles V.
And the fifth one was Napoleon
Bonaparte.
And the sixth one was Benito Mussolini.
Now right now, that's six.
And when the seventh comes, he is going
to restore
the Holy Roman Empire. He which is also
called Babylon the Great.
So now, once he restore it
he will be the eighth
head
that ruled over
all of the Gentile dynasty.
Where's he going to come from? He's
going to come from among the European
Union.
So I just gave you the name of the seven
horns.
Which are seven men that tried to
restore the Holy Roman Empire.
And now
you can go
and purchase the book from the Israelite
God, the four winds of heaven
and you will get the biblical and the
historical facts
for yourself.
Don't have to say.
All right.
Thank you for that. Hope that answered
your question as we move on to our next
one. Next one, Mrs. Golden Martin asks,
"Are there any Bible verses that inform
us if God tells us when we are going to
die?"
Um
not that I have um seen in the pages of
the book unless I mean the Lord can
always send a message to anybody, but uh
for you individually
but let's go into um
Deuteronomy. Deuteronomy the 28th
chapter and let's see what it says
there.
Deuteronomy 28.
And when you get there, brother
let's pick it up at that verse uh 60
six. Deuteronomy 28
and pick it up at verse
66. 65 and read read down.
64, brother. That sound even better. Go
ahead.
And the Lord shall scatter thee among
all people from the one end of the earth
even unto the other.
And there thou shalt serve other gods
which neither thou nor thy fathers have
known
even wood and stone.
And among these nations shalt thou find
no ease.
Neither shall the sole of thy foot have
rest.
But the Lord shall give thee there a
trembling heart and failing of eyes and
sorrow of mind.
And thy life shall hang in doubt before
thee.
And thou shalt fear day and night
and shall have none assurance of thy
life.
So if you don't have none assurance of
thy life, that mean that your time could
be at any time. There you go.
No one can really
put a chart on that, but uh we just want
to make sure we with the Lord whenever
that may happen. And even Jesus, when he
was in the flesh, he was telling his
disciples that, "Hey, it's a daytime
was always too
cuz we live in a very wicked world
and um that's how it is set up now.
So
as far as asking about, you know, Bible
verse for yourself
we can answer that for you. We can just
say that, you know, our time is always
and just serve God with all our heart
until the end.
Right. And that what you quoted,
Cornell, is in St. John chapter 7 verse
6. Yes.
>> Yeah, that's it. Yeah.
Where Jesus told his disciples, he said,
"My time ain't come yet, but your time
is always." Yeah. Yeah. He was talking
to his brothers that didn't believe in
him. Yes, sir.
Mhm. Yeah, his brothers. Thank you.
Yeah. Mhm.
So Do you have
>> Go ahead, guest caller.
This is what
>> [clears throat]
>> we have asked the question, your time
could be anytime.
That's right.
Yeah, so hey
stay prayed up and stay right with God.
All right.
>> have to be sick to die.
Absolutely. No, you don't.
No, you don't. All right, we hope that
answered your question there.
As we continue to move on to our next
one.
Moving on, M W M S God's son asks, "Do
we supposed to call someone a bishop?"
Julius. Yes.
>> Can you call someone a bishop? Yes, sir.
Let's go to first Peter. It's it's it's
it's allowed. First Peter chapter 2.
Mhm.
Go a couple of places here.
First Peter chapter 2, brother Tenzel.
One verse.
Look what the Look what Peter wrote.
First Peter
chapter 2 and read verse 25.
For ye were as sheep going astray.
But are now returned unto the shepherd
and bishop of your souls. Yes. Now,
let's go to first Timothy the third
chapter.
First Timothy
chapter 3.
First Timothy chapter 3
and read
verse 1 and 2.
This is a true saying, if a man desire
the office of a bishop he desireth a
good work. Yeah, that means he's a
overseer. Go ahead.
A bishop then must be blameless
the husband of one wife
vigilant, sober, of good behavior
given to hospitality
apt to teach. Uh-huh.
Not given to wine
no striker, not greedy of filthy lucre,
but patient, not a brawler, not
covetous.
But one that ruleth well
Go ahead.
But one that ruleth well his own house
having his children in subjection with
all gravity. So this is a man that's got
to get with children.
So it it is allowed.
Indeed it is. All right. Hope that
answered your question, sister Deborah.
Time is a ticking. Yes, it is. Sai Amar
Israel asks, "Was that the law that was
given at
at Sinai on Pentecost? Exodus 19 verse
1.
And was it confirmed
in Acts 2 on Pentecost?"
All right, looks like Exodus 19 and 1 is
the first question, was that law given
at Mount Sinai on Pentecost?
Let's go there, Tenzel, read that and
the guest caller will take it from
there.
In the third month, when the children of
Israel were gone forth out of the land
of Egypt, the same day came they into
the wilderness of Sinai.
So the first thing is it says, "Was the
law
given
at Sinai on Pentecost?"
Go to Exodus and read it. 19 and 1.
Okay, pick it up at the top of there
again, Tenzel.
In the third month when the children of
Israel were gone forth out of the land
of Egypt the same day came they into the
wilderness of Sinai.
Now, see, I can see why
people would assume that. Yeah. The
reason is
is because you have to go to the
Passover. This Passover was in the first
month, which was Abib.
Then the second month is Zif.
You know, ZIF, and the third one is
Sivan.
Do now.
And after Passover,
then you count 3 days and 3 nights, and
then your first
day of the week, which would be Sunday,
you count
seven sabbaths,
and you go to the next, which is 50.
That's where Pentecost come from.
Do now.
It looks plausible. However, you don't
have no scripture that you can read and
say it happened.
So, we don't know
what day
that God stood on Mount Sinai and gave
you the 10 Commandments.
You cannot say it's Pentecost cuz you
ain't got no scripture to say it.
Even though it's the third month, and
Abib was the first month.
If there's no
>> Mhm.
or we can't teach it.
That's all I have to say.
All right.
So, we're going to leave it right there
as we continue to move on to our next
one.
Yes, Bobby Reed asks, "Is it okay to
bear arms for protection?"
Is it okay to bear arms for protection?
You better make sure you know the laws
of the city
and state that you are in because you
can get into big trouble if you go
outside of that law. Uh let's open that
up to the panel.
Peter had a sword, didn't he?
Yep.
Indeed, he did.
And uh
>> the Lord tell
Live by the sword, what you going to do,
by?
Die by it. Die.
Oh, that's simple.
So, uh
I'm going to arm myself
with the Father and Jesus.
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah, that's God.
So, whatever you
Well, I don't have an answer for it.
That's right. Yep. I like how you going
to arm yourself with the Father and
Jesus cuz the Lord said, "No weapon
formed against you shall prosper then."
Thank you. That's all I have to
Can we
>> Yes, sir. Can we read that Psalms 44:6?
Psalms 44:6.
>> Yeah.
I like that guest caller. That's the
best weapon.
44:6.
6 and 7. Read it when you get it,
Tenzel.
For I will not trust in my bow, neither
shall my sword save me.
But thou has saved us from our enemies,
and has put them to shame that hate us.
Mhm.
Yes, sir. I'mma trust the Lord. I ain't
going to trust in my bow or my sword.
I'm going to trust in the Lord.
On my pistol.
Yeah.
I'm going to trust in the Lord.
Yeah. Sir.
That is it, indeed. So,
all right. So, um
Sister Deborah, I believe that we now
getting ready to take a trip into new
territory.
At
I'm into tonight's Q&A for
and for the 20 8 2026.
I wanted to ask Isaiah 45:5.
Okay, Sister Deborah, you having a
little technical difficulty there.
So, can you take it from the top again?
Yes.
Yeah, you still having it.
>> Okay. Okay, see, she'll be coming back
in. Were you going to say something,
Brother Julius?
No.
Okay. She um
I think she'll be trying to come back
in, but um
Yeah, we have we've had a great session
tonight.
And uh we can't even trust
That's right. Okay, go ahead, Sister. We
can hear you now.
>> Okay. Can't even trust in our internet,
but you back. Right. Okay, you can hear
me, right? Loud and clear. All right.
Sky Rider asks, "In Isaiah 45:17
and Ephesians 3:21,
can you explain what the world without
end means?"
All right, let's go to that Isaiah 45.
Isaiah 45, Tenzel.
And let's pick it up at that verse 17,
and they want to know
what does that world without end mean?
Uh we know the Lord created the world to
be inhabited, so it will be here. But go
ahead, read it, brother. But Israel
shall be saved in the Lord with an
everlasting salvation.
You shall not be ashamed nor confounded
world without end.
Mhm.
Um
Keep reading, brother.
For thus saith the Lord that created the
heavens, God himself that formed the
earth and made it. He hath established
it. He created it not in vain. He formed
it to be inhabited. I am the Lord, and
there is none else.
All right. So, he created the earth to
be inhabited, so
There ain't going to be no end to it.
Ain't going to be no end. It's going to
be right here.
Mhm. So,
>> Ecclesiastes 1.
Forever and ever
and ever.
That long, Tenzel? That long, brother.
He just going to renew the face of the
earth.
Where you at, um Julius? Ecclesiastes
Ecclesiastes uh
Uh 4.
Yeah.
One generation passeth away, and another
generation cometh.
But the earth
abideth forever.
World without end.
Yep, that's it. Okay.
Hope that answered your question,
and we're going to move on to our next
one with time running up on us, Deborah.
Uh yes.
>> Ephesians 3:21, too, right? Yes.
Let's run there right quick, Tenzel.
Ephesians 3:21.
And we're going to open that up, too.
Oh, okay, that says the same thing. We
answered it, but read it, brother.
Unto him be glory in the church by
Christ Jesus throughout all ages, world
without end. World without end, so
we answered that even though you
That's caller.
Same thing. Mhm. Yeah, even though you
brought it to us from a different angle
in that Isaiah 45. Next question,
Deborah.
Yes, Shaniqua Akujo B asks for you to
elaborate
on the phrase, "But the fearful" in
Revelation 21:8.
What does it mean?
Revelation
>> 21, you said? Mhm.
All right. And verse 8. Let's go there,
Tenzel.
And let's read that.
And
if someone would like, we can we'll turn
over to the panel after the word
fearful. That's their question, right?
Yes.
Pick it up at verse 7.
He that overcometh shall inherit all
things, and I will be his God, and he
shall be my son.
But the fearful,
and unbelieving,
and the abominable,
and murderers, and whoremongers, and
sorcerers, and idolaters, and all liars
shall have their part in the lake which
burneth with fire and brimstone, which
is the second death.
You explain it to us.
So, you want to know what fearful mean?
Yeah.
>> Yes, but the fearful, what does that
mean?
These are people that will not that that
afraid to deal with the uncut word of
God.
Mhm.
Like you won't teach it to them. You you
don't want to fall out with your
families.
Or either like in some uh
countries, like in some Muslim
countries, they're killing people right
now that profess to that profess to be
Christians. Yep.
So, they won't teach it.
Mhm.
But the Lord said, "If you uh
uh uh save or lose your life
uh uh
for my sake, you going to save it."
Yeah. But if But if But if you
uh uh
Try to save your life.
Try to save your life, you can use lose
it. That's all it is. The people is
afraid to teach the truth wherever. Or
either you don't want your friends to
turn away from you. They don't want your
momma and your pop father to turn away
from you. You won't to your parent
got that Christmas tree there, you know
that's pagan, you shouldn't do that.
Are you going to tell him, "Well, we
go to church on Easter Sunday morning,
that's pagan."
Jesus didn't die Good Friday and rise
Sunday morning. You don't want to tell
them that. Well, mother's in heaven. No,
my mother's in the graveyard.
All right.
Yeah. People are fearful. That's what
people believe talking about.
One that's fearful
that fear
repercussion. Just like he did when
when the Lord gave that parable
of the sower and the seed.
You know.
Like some fell on
stony ground or something said when the
persecution came, they turned away from
it.
The word.
Yeah.
Yeah. But that's something
Mhm. Thank you.
I had the verse 6.
What you say, Tenzel?
No, what you said fearful to compromise
with that Revelation 6 when he told told
the how the rocks to fall on us and hide
us from the face of him that sit up on
the throne and from the wrath of the
lamb.
Mhm. Yeah, and
like you read in that 7, he that
overcomes shall inherit all things.
That's the key word, overcome.
And serve God.
Sister Deborah, final question of the
evening.
Uh the time is 9:01.
Oh, all right.
Well, we want to thank everybody
from all around the world who sent in
those questions. We want to say thank
you.
We appreciate you tuning in with us and
we have ran out of time. If you
submitted a question we didn't get to
it, please don't resubmit it. Sister
Deborah take it, put it in rotation, and
we will deal with that question next
week. So, please, until we all come
together again, be safe, be blessed,
stay prayed
and may the Lord have mercy on us all as
brother Tenzel closes us out.
Our Father which are in heaven,
hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come,
thy will be done in earth as it is in
heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread
and forgive us of our debts as we
forgive our debtors.
And lead us not into temptation, but
deliver us from evil. For thine is the
kingdom and the power and the glory
forever.
In Jesus'